In some cases, it's because they're bad or unethical, but often, they've taken us to the wrong objectives. And this is unacceptable. This has to stop. How are we going to correct these wrongs? How are we going to choose the right course? It's not going to be easy. For years, I've worked with talented teams and they've chosen the right objectives and the wrong objectives. Many have succeeded, others of them have failed. And today I'm going to share with you what really makes a difference -- that's what's crucial, how and why they set meaningful and audacious goals, the right goals for the right reasons. Let's go back to 1975. Yep, this is me. I've got a lot to learn, I'm a computer engineer, I've got long hair, but I'm working under Andy Grove, who's been called the greatest manager of his or any other era. Andy was a superb leader and also a teacher, and he said to me, "John, it almost doesn't matter what you know. Execution is what matters the most." And so Andy invented a system called "Objectives and Key Results." It kind of rolls off the tongue, doesn't it? And it's all about excellent execution. So here's a classic video from the 1970s of professor Andy Grove. (Video) Andy Grove: The two key phrases of the management by objective systems are the objectives and the key results, and they match the two purposes. The objective is the direction. The key results have to be measured, but at the end you can look and without any argument say, "Did I do that, or did I not do that?" Yes. No. Simple. John Doerr: That's Andy. Yes. No. Simple. Objectives and Key Results, or OKRs, are a simple goal-setting system and they work for organizations, they work for teams, they even work for individuals. The objectives are what you want to have accomplished. The key results are how I'm going to get that done. Objectives. Key results. What and how. But here's the truth: many of us are setting goals wrong, and most of us are not setting goals at all. A lot of organizations set objectives and meet them. They ship their sales, they introduce their new products, they make their numbers, but they lack a sense of purpose to inspire their teams. So how do you set these goals the right way? First, you must answer the question, "Why?" Why? Because truly transformational teams combine their ambitions to their passion and to their purpose, and they develop a clear and compelling sense of why. I want to tell you a story. I work with a remarkable entrepreneur. Her name is Jini Kim. She runs a company called Nuna. Nuna is a health care data company. And when Nuna was founded, they used data to serve the health needs of lots of workers at large companies. And then two years into the company's life, the federal government issued a proposal to build the first ever cloud database for Medicaid. Now, you'll remember that Medicaid is that program that serves 70 million Americans, our poor, our children and people with disabilities. Nuna at the time was just 15 people and this database had to be built in one year, and they had a whole set of commitments that they had to honor, and frankly, they weren't going to make very much money on the project. This was a bet-your-company moment, and Jini seized it. She jumped at the opportunity. She did not flinch. Why? Well, it's a personal why. Jini's younger brother Kimong has autism. And when he was seven, he had his first grand mal seizure at Disneyland. He fell to the ground. He stopped breathing. Jini's parents are Korean immigrants. They came to the country with limited resources speaking little English, so it was up to Jini to enroll her family in Medicaid. She was nine years old. That moment defined her mission, and that mission became her company, and that company bid on, won and delivered on that contract. Here's Jini to tell you why. (Video) Jini Kim: Medicaid saved my family from bankruptcy, and today it provides for Kimong's health and for millions of others. Nuna is my love letter to Medicaid. Every row of data is a life whose story deserves to be told with dignity. JD: And Jini's story tells us that a compelling sense of why can be the launchpad for our objectives. Remember, that's what we want to have accomplished. And objectives are significant, they're action-oriented, they are inspiring, and they're a kind of vaccine against fuzzy thinking. You think a rockstar would be an unlikely user of Objectives and Key Results, but for years, Bono has used OKRs to wage a global war against poverty and disease, and his ONE organization has focused on two really gorgeous, audacious objectives. The first is debt relief for the poorest countries in the world. The next is universal access to anti-HIV drugs. Now, why are these good objectives? Let's go back to our checklist. Significant? Check. Concrete? Yes. Action-oriented? Yes. Inspirational? Well, let's just listen to Bono. (Video) Bono: So you're passionate? How passionate? What actions does your passion lead you to do? If the heart doesn't find a perfect rhyme with the head, then your passion means nothing. The OKR framework cultivates the madness, the chemistry contained inside it. It gives us an environment for risk, for trust, where failing is not a fireable offense. And when you have that sort of structure and environment and the right people, magic is around the corner. JD: I love that. OKRs cultivate the madness, and magic is right around the corner. This is perfect. So with Jini we've covered the whys, with Bono the whats of goal-setting. Let's turn our attention to the hows. Remember, the hows are the key results. That's how we meet our objectives. And good results are specific and time-bound. They're aggressive but realistic. They're measurable, and they're verifiable. Those are good key results. In 1999, I introduced OKRs to Google's cofounders, Larry and Sergey. Here they are, 24 years old in their garage. And Sergey enthusiastically said he'd adopt them. Well, not quite. What he really said was, "We don't have any other way to manage this company, so we'll give it a go." (Laughter) And I took that as a kind of endorsement. But every quarter since then, every Googler has written down her objectives and her key results. They've graded them, and they've published them for everyone to see. And these are not used for bonuses or for promotions. They're set aside. They're used for a higher purpose, and that's to get collective commitment to truly stretch goals. In 2008, a Googler, Sundar Pichai, took on an objective which was to build the next generation client platform for the future of web applications -- in other words, build the best browser. He was very thoughtful about how he chose his key results. How do you measure the best browser? It could be ad clicks or engagement. No. He said: numbers of users, because users are going to decide if Chrome is a great browser or not.
Dans certains cas, c'est parce qu'ils sont mauvais, ou immoraux, mais souvent, ils nous ont menés vers les mauvais objectifs. Et cela est inacceptable. Ceci doit s'arrêter. Comment va-t-on corriger ces erreurs ? Comment va-t-on choisir la bonne voie ? Ça ne va pas être facile. J'ai longtemps travaillé avec des équipes de talent et elles ont choisi les bons objectifs et les mauvais objectifs. Beaucoup ont réussi, d'autres ont échoué. Et aujourd'hui, je vais partager avec vous ce qui fait vraiment la différence - c'est ce qui est crucial, comment et pourquoi elles se fixent des objectifs sérieux et audacieux, les bons objectifs pour les bonnes raisons. Retournons en 1975. Ouais, c'est moi. J'ai beaucoup à apprendre, je suis ingénieur informatique, j'ai les cheveux longs, mais je travaille sous Andy Grove, qui a été nommé le meilleur manager de son époque et de toutes les autres. Andy était un superbe leader et aussi un professeur. Il m'a dit : « John, ce que tu sais n'a presque pas d'importance. La réalisation, c'est ce qui est le plus important. » Et donc, Andy inventa un système appelé « Objectifs et résultats clés » Ça sonne bien, n'est-ce pas ? Et tout tourne autour de la réalisation parfaite. Alors, voici une vidéo classique des années 70 du Professeur Andy Grove. « Les deux phrases clés de la gestion par les systèmes d'objectifs sont les objectifs et les résultats clés et ils correspondent à leurs deux buts. L'objectif est la direction. Les résultats doivent être mesurés, mais à la fin, on peut regarder et sans argumenter, dire : « Ai-je fait cela, oui ou non ? » Oui. Non. Simple. John Doerr : C'est bien Andy ! Oui. Non. Facile. Les objectifs et résultats clés ou ORC, sont un système simple pour se fixer des objectifs et ils fonctionnent pour des organismes, pour des équipes et même pour les individus. Les objectifs sont ce qu'on veut avoir accompli. Les résultats clés sont comment je vais faire pour y arriver. Objectifs. Résultats clés. Quoi et comment. Mais voici la vérité : nous sommes beaucoup à mal fixer nos objectifs et la plupart ne s'en fixent même pas. Beaucoup d'entreprises atteignent leurs objectifs. Elles expédient leurs produits, en lancent de nouveaux et font du profit, mais elles n'ont pas de but pour motiver leurs équipes. Alors, comment bien fixer ces objectifs dès le départ ? Premièrement, vous devez répondre à la question « Pourquoi ? » Pourquoi ? Parce que des équipes vraiment transformationnelles combinent leurs ambitions à leur passion et à leur but, et elles développent une vision claire du pourquoi. Voici une petite histoire. Je travaille avec une formidable entrepreneuse. Son nom est Jini Kim. Elle gère une entreprise appelée Nuna. C'est une société de traitement de données médicales. Quand Nuna a été créée, ils traitaient les données médicales d'employés de grandes entreprises. Deux ans après, le gouvernement a publié la proposition de créer la toute première base de données de Medicaid sur le cloud. Et vous vous rappelez que Medicaid est le programme qui touche 70 millions d'Américains, les pauvres, les enfants et les personnes handicapées. Seulement 15 personnes travaillaient alors à Nuna et cette base de données devait être faite en un an, et ils avaient de nombreux engagements à honorer, et franchement, ils n'allaient pas gagner beaucoup avec ce projet. C'était un de ces moments à quitte ou double, et Jini l'a saisi. Elle a sauté sur l'occasion. Elle n'a pas hésité. Pourquoi ? Parce que pour Jini, c'est personnel. Kimong, son petit frère, est autiste. À sept ans, il a fait sa première crise d'épilepsie à Disneyland. Il est tombé sur le sol. Il a arrêté de respirer. Les parents de Jini sont des immigrants coréens. Ils sont arrivés dans le pays avec peu de ressources parlant très peu anglais. C'est donc Jini qui a dû inscrire sa famille à Medicaid. Elle avait alors neuf ans. Ce moment a défini sa mission, et cette mission a défini son entreprise. Cette entreprise a remporté le contrat et l'a exécuté. Jini vous explique pourquoi. « Ma famille a évité la pauvreté grâce à Medicaid. Aujourd'hui, c'est ce qui soutient Kimong et des millions de personnes. Nuna, c'est ma lettre d'amour à Medicaid. Chaque ligne de données est une vie qui mérite d'être racontée avec respect. » Cette histoire nous explique que le « pourquoi » peut être le tremplin de nos objectifs. Souvenez-vous, c'est ce qu'on veut avoir accompli. Les objectifs sont importants, ils reposent sur l'action, ils sont inspirants et ils ont l'effet d'un vaccin contre les idées vagues. Pour une vedette, la technique de l'ORC n'est sûrement pas importante et pourtant, Bono l'a utilisée pendant des années pour mener une guerre contre la pauvreté et la maladie. Son organisation ONE se concentre sur deux objectifs vraiment grandioses et audacieux. D'abord, réduire la dette des pays les plus pauvres au monde. Ensuite, rendre accessible le traitement contre le VIH. Pourquoi ces objectifs sont-ils bons ? Revenons à notre liste. Importants ? Oui. Concrets ? Oui. Pragmatiques ? Oui. Inspirants ? Écoutons ce qu'en dit Bono. « Vous êtes passionnés ? À quel point ? Quelles actions avez-vous accomplies ? Si le cœur et l'esprit ne battent pas au même rythme, alors, votre passion n'est rien. La technique ORC cultive la folie, la chimie qui s'y trouve. Ça crée un environnement propice au risque, à la confiance, où l'échec n'est pas synonyme de licenciement. Fort de cette structure et de cet environnement, et entouré des bonnes personnes, la magie opère. » JD : C'est génial. L'ORC cultive la folie, et la magie opère. C'est parfait. Donc, Jini nous a expliqué pourquoi, Bono nous a expliqué l'ABC des objectifs. Maintenant, voyons les façons d'y arriver. Ces façons sont les résultats clés pour atteindre les objectifs. De bons résultats sont précis et contraints. Ils sont agressifs, mais réalistes. Ils sont mesurables et vérifiables. Voilà de bons résultats clés. En 1999, j'ai introduit les ORC auprès des cofondateurs de Google, Larry et Sergey. Les voici, à 24 ans, dans leur garage. Sergey a dit avec enthousiasme qu'il voulait les adopter. Enfin, pas tout à fait. Ce qu'il a vraiment dit, c'est : « Nous n'avons pas d'autre moyen de gérer cette entreprise, donc, essayons. » (Rires) Et j'ai pris ça pour une approbation. Mais, depuis, tous les trimestres, tous les Googlers ont écrit leurs objectifs et leurs résultats clés. Ils les ont classés et les ont publiés afin que tout le monde les voie. Ils ne sont pas utilisés pour les bonus ou les promotions. Ils sont mis de côté. Ils sont utilisés dans un but plus grand, celui d'un engagement collectif à atteindre les objectifs. En 2008, un Googler, Sundar Pichai, a décidé d'un objectif, celui de bâtir la nouvelle plateforme client pour le futur des applications web. En d'autres termes, développer le meilleur navigateur. Il a beaucoup réfléchi en choisissant ses résultats clés. Comment mesurer le meilleur navigateur ? Le nombre de clics sur les pubs ou l'engagement. Non. Il s'est dit : le nombre d'utilisateurs parce que les utilisateurs décideront si Chrome est un navigateur génial ou pas.
So he had this one three-year-long objective: build the best browser. And then every year he stuck to the same key results, numbers of users, but he upped the ante. In the first year, his goal was 20 million users and he missed it. He got less than 10. Second year, he raised the bar to 50 million. He got to 37 million users. Somewhat better. In the third year, he upped the ante once more to a hundred million. He launched an aggressive marketing campaign, broader distribution, improved the technology, and kaboom! He got 111 million users. Here's why I like this story, not so much for the happy ending, but it shows someone carefully choosing the right objective and then sticking to it year after year after year. It's a perfect story for a nerd like me. Now, I think of OKRs as transparent vessels that are made from the whats and hows of our ambitions. What really matters is the why that we pour into those vessels. That's why we do our work. OKRs are not a silver bullet.
Donc, il avait cet objectif à trois ans : développer le meilleur navigateur. Puis, chaque année, il gardait les mêmes résultats clés, le nombre d'utilisateurs, mais en relevant la barre. La première année, son but était 20 millions d'utilisateurs, il a échoué. Il en a eu moins de 10. La deuxième année, il est monté à 50 millions. Il a eu 37 millions d'utilisateurs. Un peu mieux. La troisième année, il a de nouveau monté la barre à une centaine de millions. Il a lancé une campagne marketing agressive, une distribution plus large, une technologie améliorée et badaboum ! Il a atteint les 111 millions d'utilisateurs. Voilà pourquoi j'aime cette histoire, pas tant pour la fin heureuse, mais ça montre quelqu'un qui choisit avec précaution les bons objectifs et qui s'y tient année après année. C'est une histoire parfaite pour un geek comme moi. Je vois désormais les ORC comme des récipients transparents composés des quoi et des comment de nos ambitions. Ce qui importe vraiment, c'est le pourquoi que nous mettons dans ces récipients. C'est pourquoi nous faisons notre travail. Les ORC ne sont pas une solution miracle.
They're not going to be a substitute for a strong culture or for stronger leadership, but when those fundamentals are in place, they can take you to the mountaintop. I want you to think about your life for a moment. Do you have the right metrics? Take time to write down your values, your objectives and your key results. Do it today. If you'd like some feedback on them, you can send them to me. I'm john@whatmatters.com. If we think of the world-changing goals of an Intel, of a Nuna, of Bono, of Google, they're remarkable: ubiquitous computing,
Ils ne remplaceront pas une culture forte ou un fort leadership, mais quand ces fondamentaux existent, ils peuvent vous transporter au sommet de la montagne. Je veux que vous réfléchissiez un instant à votre vie. Avez-vous les bonnes mesures ? Prenez le temps d'écrire vos valeurs, vos objectifs et vos résultats clés. Faites-le aujourd'hui. Si vous voulez un avis, vous pouvez me les envoyer. Je suis john@whatmatters.com Si nous pensons aux objectifs qui changent le monde, à un Intel, un Nuna, Bono, Google, ils sont fantastiques : l'informatique ubiquitaire,
affordable health care, high-quality for everyone, ending global poverty, access to all the world's information. Here's the deal: every one of those goals is powered today by OKRs. Now, I've been called the Johnny Appleseed of OKRs for spreading the good gospel according to Andy Grove, but I want you to join me in this movement. Let's fight for what it is that really matters, because we can take OKRs beyond our businesses. We can take them to our families, to our schools, even to our governments. We can hold those governments accountable. We can transform those informations. We can get back on the right track if we can and do measure what really matters. Thank you. (Applause)
les soins abordables, de la haute qualité pour tous, la fin de la pauvreté mondiale, l'accès à toute l'information au niveau mondial. Voici ce que nous avons : chacun de ces objectifs est soutenu aujourd'hui par les ORC. Désormais, on m'appelle le chantre des ORC diffusant la bonne parole d'Andy Grove, mais je veux que vous me rejoigniez dans ce mouvement. Battons-nous pour ce qui compte vraiment, parce que nous pouvons appliquer les ORC au-delà de nos entreprises. Nous pouvons les appliquer dans nos familles, dans nos écoles, même dans nos gouvernements. Nous pouvons tenir ces gouvernements pour responsables. Nous pouvons transformer ces informations. Nous pouvons revenir sur le droit chemin si nous pouvons mesurer et mesurons ce qui compte vraiment. Merci. (Applaudissements)